Utkarsh Patel

+1 (647)-779-8261 • Brampton, ON L6Y4K9 • github.com/UtkarshPatel9934 • linkedin.com/in/utkarshpateldeveloper

Web Developer

Front-end Developer | Back-end Developer

Graduate in Internet Application and Web Development achieved **4.0 GPA** along with **Academic Distinction Award.** In addition, **2+ years** of knowledge in using wide range of web development skillsets to create robust web applications, and built it more secure, effective as well as achieve attractive user interface.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ST. Clair College - *Windsor, ON*

06/2022 - Present

Web Developer

Served as a Web developer to create a robust Time Tracking Software for Mega Mold International.

- Hired by ST. Clair College as a Web developer, create a Time Tracking application, which helps Mega Mold International Windsor-based Company to track exact times for their employees.
- Determining the overall structure of the Time Tracking Application website and working to accomplish a responsive design.
- Helped in creating the application mockups using Figma and Balsamiq Wireframe.
- Developed a robust application using previous skills-sets learned at ST. Clair College.
- Demonstrate and implement the web programming languages like HTML5, CSSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Google Sheets, Laravel etc. including frameworks such as React js to develop Single Page Applications for Mega Mold International.

SK Corporate - *Gujarat, IN*

07/2021 - 12/2021

Web Developer

Spearheaded in development company website to increase its web presence.

- Designed multiple webpages using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, JavaScript along with frameworks and libraries such as Bootstrap, jQuery, jQuery UI, React.js, Angular, Laravel etc.
- Collaborated with UI/UX design teams to improve Customer Experience rate by 20%.
- Crafted 10+ distinct mock-ups and clickable prototypes of the websites using Figma software and Balsamiq Wireframes.
- Performed code reviews, bug fixes troubleshooting issues and enhanced efficiency by 45% to reach targeted results.

Aum Enterprise - Gujarat, IN

06/2020 - 06/2021

Front-end Developer

Served as a team lead for the Front-end Developer team and roles comprised:

• Optimized the web pages in order that it loads 30% faster and more efficiently than the previous one.

- Determined the overall structure of the website and worked to accomplish a responsive design which leads to an increase in the customer base for the company website by 60% over the internet.
- Utilized the reusable code across 3+ webpages of the company website to reduce the duplication of the code by a large proportion.
- Built the company website with a variety of markup languages to write web pages and incorporate 4+ programming languages such as PHP, C#, ASP.NET, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, and jQuery UI in order to forge a robust web application.

FROID Inc. - Gujarat, IN

05/2019 - 05/2020

Web Designer | Logo Designer

Hired as a designer to produce a web design for the company which includes:

- Fabricated 10+ mock-ups and created several clickable prototypes for several web pages of the company website.
- Transformed 2+ mock-ups and clickable design of the webpages into the actual website using 3+ programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and jQuery UI.
- Built 3 different logos and letterhead designs for the company using editing software such as Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator.
- Redesigned letterhead and logo of the Company, which results in a 65% boost in the product sales, according to the request of the manager.

EDUCATION

ST. Clair College - Windsor, ON

05/2021 - 07/2022

Associate Degree – Internet Application and Web Development

4.0 GPA | Academic Distinction (Semester 1st to 4th)

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, PHP, C#, C, ASP.NET MVC
- Frameworks: React.js, Angular, Laravel, jQuery
- Database: MySQL, SQL Server, Microsoft SQL, PhpMyAdmin, MariaDB
- Software: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Brackets, PHP Storm, PhpMyAdmin, Net Beans, GitHub, MS Office Suite, Microsoft Teams, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Acrobat, Figma, Balsamiq Wireframe, XAMPP, WAMP
- Operating System: Windows 7/8/8.1/10, Linux, XP, Apple macOS

Reference: Peers, Supervisors, Managers, and Instructors' references are available upon request.